# Mohamed Shaheed A

Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India

mohamedshaheed8055@gmail.com



7339086231



linkedin.com/in/mohamed-shaheed-a-9497731b3



https://shaheedams.github.io/portfolio/

# Summary

Hello, my name is Mohamed Shaheed A. I am a self-taught Programmer. Over the past 4 Months, I have primarily worked for companies as a Web Developer and Front end Developer intern that specialize in enterprise web applications. I have hands on skills in Html, CSS, JavaScript, React Js, core Java, java, OOPS, SQL and going on learning...

Projects:

### 1.CresChat:

It was my final year college project, Basically our project was a organized social media for students, our primary goal is to make a interaction between students and professors in our website, in which you can post questions, doubts and professors can clear your doubts and questions. And another feature is professors can post something use full posts like related to education articles, blogs ect...

Technologies Worked With:

Frontend Tools: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Backend Tools: Node.js, Express.js,

Database: mongo DB.

### 2.Tesla Website Clone:

Basically it was a clone of Tesla website using React.js framework. I used react.js features like React Hooks, Styled Components, Material UI...

Technologies Worked With:

Frontend Tools: HTML, CSS, Javascript,

Framework: React.js.

### 3. Swiggy Menu Clone:

It was a clone of Swiggy Menu using React.js framework. I used react.js features like React Hooks, Styled Components, Material UI...

Technologies Worked With:

Frontend Tools: HTML, CSS, Javascript,

Framework: React.js.

### 4.PickBazar(E-Commerce Website):

It was a e-commerce website inspired from some e-commerce website like Flipkart, amazon, Ajio and created using React.js. Then I used react.js features like React Hooks, Styled Components, Material UI...

Technologies Worked With:

Frontend Tools: HTML, CSS, Javascript,

Framework : React.js.

Key Tools:

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React JS, BootStrap.

# **Experience**

## Full Stack Developer Intern

The Sparks Foundation

May 2021 - Jun 2021 (2 months) Project: BASIC BANKING SYSTEM

My Task was to create and deploy a banking web application with certain functions like transferring money, showing Transaction details, balance ect...

Technologies used:

Frontend Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Backend Tools: Node.js, Express.js,

Database: Mongo DB



### Web Development Intern

Exposys Data Labs

Apr 2021 - May 2021 (2 months)

Task: Create a website

Turn design pages and specific components into a Functional website using HTML, CSS, JavaScript.

Technologies used:

Frontend Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript,

### **Education**



# BSA Crescent Institute of Science and Technology

BCA, Cloud technology and information security 2018 - 2021 82%

# **Licenses & Certifications**



React js - Udemy

UC-0338591a-9603-4595-a61d-d05be1092b0f



Web Developer Internship - Exposys Data Labs



**Web Developer Internship** - The Sparks Foundation

### Skills

JavaScript • HTML5 • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) • Front-end Development • React.js • Core Java • Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) • Java • SQL